forcefactor.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy - Force Factor

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Welcome to Force Factor ([www.ForceFactor.com](http://www.forcefactor.com/) or the "Website"). This policy (the "Privacy Policy") explicates our practices regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of information that you may provide via this Website and certain related services. Please be sure to read this entire Privacy Policy before using or submitting information to this Website.

**Policy**  
The policy of the Website is to respect and protect the privacy of our users. To fulfill this policy, the Website agrees to exercise the precautions set forth in this Privacy Policy to maintain the confidentiality of information provided by you in connection with accessing and using the Website.

**Your Consent**  
This Privacy Policy sets forth the Website's current policies and practices with respect to nonpublic personal information of the users of the Website. By using this Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Whenever you submit information via this Website, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Our Commitment to Children's Privacy**  
Protecting the privacy of children is especially important. This Website is not intended for people under the age of 18. We never collect information from persons we know to be under the age of 18, and no part of our Website is designed to attract anyone under the age of 18. We encourage parents to talk to their children about their use of the Internet and the information they disclose to websites.

**Active Information Collection**  
Like many websites, this Website actively collects information from its users both by asking you specific questions and by permitting you to communicate directly with us via email, live chat, and/or feedback forms. Some of the information that you submit may be personally identifiable information (that is, information that can be uniquely identified as belonging to you, such as your full name, email address, mailing address, phone number, billing, credit card information, etc.).

Some areas of this Website may require you to submit information in order for you to benefit from the specified features (such as newsletter subscriptions, tips/pointers, and order processing) or to participate in a particular activity (such as sweepstakes or other promotions). You will be informed at each information collection point what information is required and what information is optional.

**Disclosure of Information**  
We may disclose your personal information to contractors or service providers that help us provide services to you or deliver products to you. For example, we will disclose your billing information to payment processors to process your order transaction, shipping address to shipping contractors to deliver a product to you, and, at times, your email address to email fulfillment contractors to send you emails from us. We may share some or all of your personal information with our parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control, in which case we will request that these affiliates honor this Privacy Policy.

If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will possess the personal information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may disclose your personal information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas, judicial proceedings, court orders, or warrants served on us; or (b) protect and defend our rights or property or the rights or property of third parties.

From time to time, we make the email addresses of those who access our Website, or otherwise provide an email address to us, available to other organizations. If you do not want us to share your email address with other companies or organizations, please let us know by calling customer service at 1-877-492-7243. 

Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers may receive telephone contact from us with information regarding products, services, and/or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such telephone calls, please let us know by calling customer service at 1-877-492-7243.

Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers may also receive telephone contact from other companies. You can, however, have your name put on our do-not-share list by calling customer service at 1-877-492-7243. You will be asked to provide us with your name and phone number. We will use reasonable efforts to remove your name from the list we share with other organizations.

We may disclose your personal information to contractors, service providers, or third-party marketers that help us provide services and deliver products or advertisements to you.

If you would like to know (a) the categories of personal information that we disclosed in the prior calendar year to third parties about you for the purposes of third-party marketing and/or (b) the names and addresses of such third parties, please contact us at 1-877-492-7243.

**Opt-Out Procedures**  
You may always opt out of receiving communications from us. To opt out of receiving future non-transactional email communications from Force Factor, please visit [www.ForceFactor.com/unsubscribe](https://www.forcefactor.com/unsubscribe) or contact us at 1-877-492-7243, Monday through Thursday from 8:00am to 9:00pm Eastern Time (US), Fridays 8:00am to 6:00pm Eastern Time (US), Saturdays 9:00am to 6:00pm Eastern Time (US), and Sundays 11:00am to 5:00pm Eastern Time (US).

**Security of Information**  
You can be assured that personal information collected through the Website is secure and is maintained in a manner consistent with current industry standards. The importance of security for all personal information associated with our users is of utmost concern to us. Your personal information is protected in several ways. Your personal information resides on a secure server that only select Force Factor employees and contractors have access to via password. In order to most efficiently serve you, credit card transactions and order fulfillment are handled by established third-party vendors, processing agents, and distribution institutions. They receive the information needed to verify and authorize your credit card or other payment information and to process and ship your order.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, you acknowledge that: (a) There are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) The security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through this Website cannot be guaranteed; and (c) Any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party. Moreover, where you use passwords, ID numbers, or other special access features on this Website, it is your responsibility to safeguard them.

**Passive Information Collection**  
As you navigate through a website, certain information can be passively collected (that is, gathered without your actively providing the information) using various technologies and means, such as Internet Protocol addresses, cookies, Internet tags, and navigational data collection.

This Website may use Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. An IP address is a number assigned to your computer by your Internet service provider (ISP) so you can access the Internet and is generally considered to be non-personally identifiable information, because in most cases an IP address is dynamic (changing each time you connect to the Internet), rather than static (unique to a particular user's computer). We use your IP address to diagnose problems with our server, report aggregate information, determine the fastest route for your computer to use in connecting to our Website, and administer and improve services to our consumers.

A "cookie" is a bit of information that a website sends to your web browser that helps the website remember information about you and your preferences. This Website uses cookies. 

"Session cookies" are temporary bits of information that are erased once you exit your web browser or otherwise turn your computer off. Session cookies are used to improve navigation on websites and to collect aggregate statistical information. This Website uses session cookies.

"Persistent cookies" are more permanent bits of information that are placed on the hard drive of your computer and stay there unless you delete them. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for a number of purposes, such as retrieving certain information you have previously provided (e.g., a username), helping to determine what areas of the website users find most valuable, and customizing the website based on your preferences. This Website uses persistent cookies.

"Internet tags" (also known as pixels, single-pixel GIFs, clear GIFs, invisible GIFs, and 1-by-1 GIFs) are smaller than cookies and tell a website server information such as the IP address and browser type related to the user’s computer. This Website uses Internet tags.

"Navigational data" (log files, server logs, and clickstream data) and Internet tags are used for system management, to improve the content of a website, market research purposes, and to communicate information to users. This Website uses navigational data.

**Internet-Based Online Advertisements**  
We, or a data provider we have engaged, may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads, content, or services. No personally identifiable information is on or connected to these cookies. Customized ads are intended to be relevant to you based on information we or an online advertising network serving the ad collect about your online activities here and elsewhere over time. For example, anonymous information collected across multiple Internet sites that you visit over time may enable the ad network to predict your preferences and show you ads that are most likely to be of interest to you. Some of these networks may participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Program. To learn more about your choices relating to networks that participate in the DAA Program, including how to opt out of this category of advertising, please visit <http://aboutads.info/choices>.

**Links**  
This Website may contain links to websites of third parties not affiliated with Force Factor. This Privacy Policy will not apply to these third-party websites and this Website is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any of these other websites, even where these third-party websites indicate a special relationship or "partnership" with this Website. In most cases, we do not disclose personally identifiable information to those responsible for the linked websites. The linked websites, however, may collect personal information from you when you visit their website. This collection of information is not subject to the control of this Website. To ensure protection of your privacy, always review the privacy policies of the websites you visit.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**  
This Privacy Policy may change over time. We may notify you by email to the email address associated with your account when we make substantive changes to this Privacy Policy. If you do not accept the changed version (for example, if you do not approve of a different way that we intend to use personal information), you may let us know by calling us at 1-877-492-7243. If you do not respond with any objections, we will assume that you consent to the changes in the Privacy Policy. Changes will not apply retroactively to personal information that was collected before the changes to the Privacy Policy were made, except as may be required by law.

**How to Contact Us**  
If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the information collection and usage practices of this Website, please contact us at 1-877-492-7243, Monday through Thursday from 8:00am to 9:00pm Eastern Time (US), Fridays 8:00am to 6:00pm Eastern Time (US), Saturdays 9:00am to 6:00pm Eastern Time (US), and Sundays 11:00am to 5:00pm Eastern Time (US).

Follow Us & Stay In The Know

Find **Force Factor** at These Retailers
